<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Travel Ukraine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_activity_city">ActivityCity</string>
    <string name="Kyiv">"Kyiv is the cradle of Slavic civilization and one of the most ancient, majestic, and beautiful cities of Europe. For good reasons, Honore de Balzac called it the Eternal City, Northern Rome. Not every European capital can be proud of such a long history and so many cultural landmarks. Kyiv’s original appearance and ancient traditions are combined seamlessly with modernity, and its distinct charm and hospitality make it one of the most appealing cities of not only Ukraine, but of the whole world.\n
Kyiv, whose history goes back over 1500 years, was named after Kyi, the elder of the two legendary brothers who created the city with their sister, Lybid. A competing legend claims that the city got its name from its first citizens, the kiyans, who maintained the Dnieper River crossing.\n
In the 9th century, Kyiv became the capital of one of the most powerful states of Eastern Ukraine: Kyivan Rus. At that time it was an important political, economic, and cultural center. After the year 988, when Prince Vladimir converted Rus to Christianity, Kyiv became a spiritual capital and is until today one of the most famous Christian cities in the world. The city lost its power when the Mongol-Tatars overran it in 1240. After that, Kyiv was a part the Grand Duchy of Lithuania, Russia, the Ukrainian Soviet Republic, and, since 1991, the capital of independent Ukraine.\n
But regardless of the numerous was and invasions that Kyiv has gone through, the city was able to preserve its ancient heritage. It is best to start discovering the Ukrainian capital from its center, the Independence Square. It is the heart of Ukraine, which beats in unison with current events. It obtained its modern look only recently – in 2001, new monuments, sculptures and fountains were built here. At the same time, a tall column with a statue of a girl holding a cranberry branch, the symbol of Ukraine's independence, was raised in its center. Today, this monument is one of the capital's most famous landmarks.\n
The main square is crossed by the legendary Khreshchatyk, Kyiv’s main street, which is almost one and a half kilometers (one mile) long. During the week, it is a dynamic center for business; on the weekends, when the street becomes closed off to vehicles, it is one of locals’ and tourists’ favorite places to stroll. The buildings on Khreshchatyk are mostly in the “Stalin-era” style, having been built after World War II. During the war, the historical center and many buildings on the main street were destroyed. When German forces entered Kyiv in 1941, the retreating Red Army mined and exploded the center of the city. Today, Khreshchatyk is the place where you can best feel the original rhythm and atmosphere of Ukraine’s capital. Here, you can listen to street musicians, watch the performances, and enjoy the sights of the blossoming chestnut trees in the spring.\n
The large number of monuments dating back to Kyivan Rus constantly remind its visitors of Kyiv’s ancient past. One example of this is the Golden Gateway, a unique sample of Old Russian military architecture, that is one of UNESCO’s World Heritage Sites. Another example is the St. Sophia Cathedral, in which wonderful Byzantine frescos survive until today. There is also the St. Michael Cathedral, famous for its shimmering mosaics. And, of course, there is Kyiv’s Pechersk Lavra, a stunning monastery complex spread on the high Dnieper banks.\n
The delicate charm of 18th century Kyiv is presented most beautifully in St. Andrew's Church, which is called the last masterpiece of the great Rastrelli. The Andriyivsky Descent, known as Kyiv’s “Montmartre,” is the most picturesque of the capital’s streets. On it, the artistic atmosphere of past century remains until today. Strolling through it now, like in times past, you will enter an atmosphere of freedom and creativity and find dozens of artistic workshops, galleries and saloons.\n
Kyiv is also famous for its unique museums. One of them, the National Museum of the Great Patriotic War (World War II), is devoted to Ukraine’s contributions to the Allies’ victory over fascism. The museum not only amazes with its astonishing number and high quality of exhibits, but also with its central statue, the ""Homeland-Mother.” The Chernobyl Museum describes one of Ukraine's most tragic days, on which the awful accident in Chernobyl’s nuclear power plant took place. Of all the wonderful museums in Kyiv, one that deserves special mention is the Bohdan and Varvara Khanenko Museum of Arts, which keeps the best collection of art in Ukraine.\n
Kyiv is among the greenest of Europe’s cities, and it is famous for its cozy parks. The Mariinsky Park is the most popular. Its main sight is the luxurious Mariinsky Palace, built in the 18th century on orders of Russia’s Empress Elizabeth. Now, it is the Ukrainian President’s official residence. Also interesting is the House with Chimeras, one of the most famous of Kyiv’s Art Nouveau buildings. This mansion, whose roof and facade are decorated with creatures similar to those who adorn the Notre Dame in Paris, is considered to be the most unusual building in Kyiv.\n
Several landmarks in Kyiv’s outskirts deserve special attention: the open air complex Pirogovo, as well as the “city-museum” Pereiaslav-Khmelnytskyi. The latter is one of Ukraine’s oldest towns, and it packs over 30 museums on its tiny territory.\n
To its visitors, Kyiv is a real marvel! This city history witnessed and participated in many important events and years of hardship and prosperity. Now, it shares its wisdom and charm with each of its guests. Kyiv’s majestic churches, fantastic landscapes, peculiar architecture, unusual museums, and unique monuments will make you fall in love, and you will dream of visiting it again and again."
</string>
    <string name="Lviv">"Lviv is the most unusual city in Ukraine, and its most colorful. It is one the country’s of most popular tourist destinations. Only Kyiv can compete with its beauty, grandness and number of amazing landmarks. Different eras, architectures, traditions, identities, temperaments, and histories have been woven into the common thread that is Lviv. On one hand, Lviv’s grandness inspires awe in its guests; on the other, its openness, elegance and inimitable warm atmosphere make this city one of the warmest and most hospitable in Ukraine.\n
The capital of the country’s west, the city owes its fascinating appearance, reminiscent of Prague, Krakow and Vienna at once, to its bright and dynamic history, which has been changing and developing for over seven and a half centuries. It is thought that Prince Daniel of Galicia founded the city in the 13th century, naming it after his son Lev. One hundred years later, Lviv was ruled by Poland, given the Magdeburg Rights, and subsequently developed very rapidly, as its diverse population grew constantly.\n
At the end of the 18th century, the city became a part of the Austro-Hungarian Empire and its name was changed to Lemberg. At that time, it became the center for Polish, German, Jewish, and Ukrainian cultures at once. It also gained a reputation for its inventions and innovations: it were Lviv’s pharmacists who invented kerosene, and a local blacksmith designed the first gas lamp.\n
During World War II, the city went under the Nazi occupation. In three gruesome years, 150,000 people were killed in Lviv’s ghetto, and 350,000 more died in concentration camps. These shocking executions greatly changed Lviv's demographics. The city itself became a part of the Soviet Union in 1944.\n
The unyielding sieges and occupations over the centuries of Lviv’s history contributed to the formation of a powerful national identity, which helped Ukraine gain its independence in 1991, with Lviv as its spiritual capital and keeper of national identity.\n
Architecturally, the city manages to combine its European influences with Soviet-era leftovers in a remarkable manner, giving the city a peculiar charm. Despite being a rather large city, a unique calmness prevails here. It makes for pleasant strolls through the city’s narrow cobblestone streets, filled with a medieval atmosphere.\n
Lviv’s historic center can be called an outdoor museum. For good reason, it was included on the list of UNESCO’s World Cultural Heritage sites – it has nearly two thousand historic, cultural and architectural monuments. The heart of the city, the Rynok Square, amazes with colorful houses, taken straight from the pages of fairytales. In its center stands the Town Hall, from which one can see breathtaking views of the city. You will get a good look at the Cathedral, in which elements of Gothic, Renaissance, Baroque, and Classicist architecture are successfully blended. You will also see the Dominican Church, the famous Armenian Apostolic Church and Lviv’s crown jewel – the beautiful St. George's Cathedral. Another fantastic panoramic view can be seen from the Lviv High Castle’s sightseeing platform.\n
All roads from Rynok Square will lead you to Lviv’s main street - Freedom Avenue. It begins at the admirable Opera House, which is considered to be one of the most beautiful in Europe. At the avenue’s epicenter stands the memorial to Taras Shevchenko, complemented by a 12 meter-high (40 feet) stele; the statue is a symbol Ukraine’s national revival.\n
It is not possible to understand Lviv’s history without visiting the Lychakiv Cemetery, which is often compared to the famous Père Lachaise Cemetery in Paris. Buried here are important public figures, politicians, writers, and composers, from not only Ukraine, but also Poland, Austria, Armenia, and others.\n
And of course, it is hard to leave Lviv without trying its famous chocolate or drinking a cup of its coffee, whose odor permeates the city. By the way, coffee was made popular all over Europe by one of Lviv’s own, the merchant and warrior Georgy Kulchinsky. In the 17th century, he rescued Vienna from siege, and received 300 sacks of coffee beans as a reward. Using the spoils, he founded in the Austrian capital the first chain of coffee houses, 300 years before Starbucks!\n
A trip to Lviv always seems like journey through time and space. However much you visit this city, you cannot claim that you have seen all its sights and unraveled all its mysteries. With each visit, you will find new surprises in this city, fascinating and impressing you with its inimitable appearance over and over again.\n
"
</string>
    <string name="Odesa">"Odesa is the third largest city and the biggest seaport in Ukraine; it is also the country’s most picturesque and multicultural city. Due to its unique charm, sunny climate, miles-long beaches, and azure sea, Odesais often called a city straight out of fairytales. The rich greenery of endless parks hugs snow-white buildings in art nouveau and neoclassicism styles.\n
Tourists flock to Odesa’s golden coast not only for the numerous sanatoriums and mineral springs that the city offers, but also for its dynamic night-life. From May to October, the city’s nightlife throbs from dusk till dawn, which helps to explain why the locals call it the ""Hedonism Capital.”\n
Odesa is a rather young city. It appeared on the map of the Russian Empire in 1794, on the order of Catherine the Great (for which the grateful citizens of Odesa erected a monument two centuries later). Several legends give clues to the origin of the city’s name. According to the most popular story, the southern capital of the Russian Empire was named (in accordance with tradition of the time) after the ancient Greek colony Odessos, on which Odesa is built. Another (less credible) tale claims that when Catherine was arguing for the city’s location, she wanted to stress that it had enough fresh water. Thus, she chose to name the city with the French expression “assez d’eau” – “enough water” – read backwards.\n
The history of Odesa is unlike the history of any other Ukrainian city. The modern parts of the city were founded by Catherine's favorite general, Gregory Potemkin, after the port Khadijbey was wrestled away from the Turks. From the very beginning, the city was built by European standards. The city’s founders were a talented bunch – Neapolitan admiral José de Ribas; military engineer France de Wollant; and the Duke of Richelieu, who became the city’s first governor. Under their guidance, Odesa quickly turned not only into an international trading hub, but also into a scientific, cultural, and educational oasis. By the time its 100th anniversary came around, Odesa had become the third most important city in the empire, after Moscow and St. Petersburg.\n
In the early 19th century a ‘free zone’ was opened in Odesa. Taking advantage of the opportunity, fugitives, criminals and dissidents rushed into the city. As the young port needed not only material resources, but also an able workforce, the officials paid little attention to dubious legal status of its numerous guests. It became a proverbial mom for them, and the city began to be known as “Odesa-mama.”\n
During the First and Second World Wars, many places in the region were ruined. But Odesa fearlessly struggled against its invaders, a struggle for which it gained the rank of ‘hero-city.’ During World War II, Soviet partisans took shelter in Odesa’s famous catacombs and fought heroically against the German and Romanian occupiers. These labyrinthine tunnels are now famous across the world for their length and complexity.\n
Throughout its history, the representatives of different nations, cultures, professions, and religions contributed to Odesa’s cultural wealth. Because of this, the city is, and always has been, one of the most diverse places in Ukraine. This fact helps to explain Odesa’s peculiar charm and sense of humor of the locals.\n
Odesa is not only an ideal place to rest, but it is also a city rich in natural and cultural resources. The best way to familiarize oneself with Odesa’s splendid architecture, breathtaking views and fantastic monuments is by walking around its historic center. Odesa is a city that is not easily forgotten. Its snow-white yachts, golden beaches, lush green gardens, and the bluest waters, cling to the heart and fill each visitor with an overwhelming desire to return to the beautiful Odesa.\n
"
</string>
    <string name="Zaporizhzhia">"Spread on both banks of the Dnieper River, Zaporizhzhia is one of the largest regional centers of Ukraine – a remarkable industrial and cultural center, and an important river port. Known across the world as the Cossacks’ motherland, Zaporizhzhia continues to protect its traditions.\n
The history of the city is intertwined with the famous Dnieper rapids and the Khortytsia Island. In the 16th century, the Cossacks – who were mainly peasants escaping from feudal oppression – founded the country known as Zaporizhian Sich here, which later came to be called the Free Cossack Republic. The Cossacks held off the Tatars’ advance on Zaporizhian lands, and guided merchant ships down the Dnieper River. They also actively participated in the national struggle against Polish occupiers. Not long after that, the freedom-loving Zaporizhian Cossacks began to worry the Russian Empire. In 1775, Catherine the Great ordered the Zaporizhian Sich to be destroyed, and the lands of the Lower Dnieper were merged with Russia.\n
To save the empire's southern borders from the Crimean Khanate, Catharine decided to build Fort Alexander not far from Khortytsia. A settlement was formed near the fortress, where the Zaporizhian Cossacks settled. The population of this small town, called Alexandrovsk at the time, slowly grew. Soon, the town turned into an important trade and traffic center. However, over the next century the town’s development slowed.\n
Only in the early 20th century Alexandrovsk, by then renamed Zaporizhzhia (which means ""beyond the rapids""), began to greatly increase its production. The most powerful hydroelectric power station in Europe - ""DnieproGES"" - was constructed there. Iron works factories were built. In the 1920s and 1930s,Zaporizhzhia became one of the most important centers of industry and power engineering in the Soviet Union.\n
The city had a hard time during the occupation, but after the Second World War, it succeeded in speedily reconstructing its industries. In the post-war period, double-deck bridges were built over the Dnieper, connecting its banks. Today, the bridges remain as a testament to the engineering and architectural prowess of the city’s constructors. From one of these bridges, one can catch a most splendid view of the “DnieproHES” dam, as well as the legendary Khortytsia Island. Today, the island is home to the historical and cultural complex “Zaporizhian Sich,” the National Museum of Zaporizhian Cossack History, and famous Theatre of Horse Riding, one of the city’s landmarks.\n
Zaporizhzhia has a special charm, as its buildings, in the so-called Stalin Empire-style, are decorated with elaborate patterns, classical columns, and porticos in the neoclassic spirit. One can admire many of them walking along the Lenin Avenue – the longest avenue in Europe! Zaporizhzhia also has many museums, the most popular ones being the Weapon History Museum and the Museum of Retro Automobiles.\n
The city’s suburbs also hold many points of interests. First, there are numerous unique burial mounds covering the Zaporizhzhia region. The most interesting one is the complex “Kamyana Mohyla” (literally, ""Stone Tomb""), made up of huge boulders that used to serve as a special sanctuary for the ancient inhabitants of Zaporizhian area. And of course, laying on the edge of the warm and tender Azov Sea, the region attracts many visitors to its resorts. The most famous of them – Berdyansk, with its sanatoriums and sand beaches – has been for a long time a favorite place for those looking to relax and rejuvenate their well-being.\n
In recent years, more and more travelers have discovered Zaporizhzhia for themselves. They come here not only to be amazed by its unique sights, but also to experience the history of the Ukrainian people and to feel the powerful spirit of freedom that was endowed to the city by the Cossacks."
</string>
    <string name="Chernivtsi">"This wonderful city is spread out at the foot of Carpathian Mountains, on the picturesque hills of the Prut River. It is an unofficial capital of the Bukovina region, and, along with Lviv, is one of the most important cultural centers in Western Ukraine. Chernivtsi distinguishes itself from other cities in the region with its bright personality, unique energy, and magical atmosphere. It fascinates with its eclectic architecture, rich cultural heritage and the spider-web like labyrinth of ancient European streets and squares.\n
By the 12th century, Chernivtsi was already a part of the Galicia–Volhynia Principality. It gained the status of a city only three centuries later, when it was absorbed by Moldavia. After that, the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth and the Ottoman Empire ruled the city, but it remained a poor and unremarkable district of Europe for over 300 years.\n
Chernivtsi’s luck change in the late 18th century, when the city, along with all of the Bukovina region, was annexed by the powerful Austro-Hungarian Empire. Over the next hundred years, due to the efforts of Emperor Franz the Second, Chernivtsi developed into one of the richest and most beautiful cities of Europe.\n
The inimitable architectural ensemble of the old city was created during the Austrian period. Miraculously, the old city passed through the two World Wars almost unscathed, and today, it draws in visitors with its gorgeous buildings that were designed by talented Viennese modernist architects.Chernivtsi was actually developed at the same time as the Austrian capital and the two cities share similar architecture, for which it is often called a “little Vienna.”\n
The remarkable interweaving of history and culture has dictated its charming image. Here, you will find elegant classicist houses standing next to solemn Catholic churches, an ornate Baroque theatre neighboring an Armenian church, and an ancient Orthodox cathedral adjoining a synagogue. But the brightest of Chernivtsi’s architectural jewels, embodying a mixture of varying styles and cultures, is rightly considered to be the housing compound of the former Bukovinian high priests (today it houses the National University). The complex, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, was created by the great Czech architect Josef Hlávka and it is amazingly beautiful. You will find traces of Moresque, Byzantine and Romanesque styles in its design.\n
One more important sight in Chernivtsi is the Central Square, whose architectural ensemble consists of decorative, old buildings giving the square its European look. The Town Hall, built in the late Classicist style in the middle of the 19th century, stands in the center of the square. Nearby, a charming Bukovinian bank and administrative building draws you in with its beauty. It is considered to be one of the finest examples of Modern style architecture in Eastern Europe. An art museum now occupies the building.\n
The breathtaking Theatre Square is decorated by the Olha Kobylyanska Music and Drama Theater, created by the architects of Vienna’s and Odesa’s opera houses. It is considered to be one of the best European theatres of its time. The title of the most original building of Chernivtsi belongs to Orthodox St Nicholas Cathedral. Because of unusual look, with its crooked cupolas “leaning” to the main dome, the temple is colloquially called ""the drunk church.” If you stare at it for a long time, you will begin to feel slightly inebriated. So, the St. Nicholas Cathedral can truly be called the most mind-blowing of the city’s sights!\n
Chernivtsi is a dynamic and extremely attractive city, never failing to fascinate its guests. Some come here to admire the city’s fine architecture; others, to walk its narrow streets and feel the inimitable spirit of Bukovina capital. But all of them, without exception, plan to return to this unique city many times again!\n
"
</string>
    <string name="IvFrankivsk">"To most tourists, Ivano-Frankivsk is the gateway to the Ukrainian Carpathians. So it is often considered to be just a transit point on the way to one of the numerous health and ski resorts of Zakarpattia. But this charming city, with its parks, lush gardens, European-styled houses, and historical monuments, is worth staying in for more than just a night.\n
Andrzej Potocki founded the city in 1662 and named it Stanyslaviv, after his father Stanyslav. It started out as a defense castle against the Crimean Tatars and as a stronghold of Polish lords in Galicia. In the late 18th century, the city was taken by the Hapsburg Empire, in whose hands it stayed until the beginning of World War I. In 1918, it became the capital of the short-lived West Ukrainian People's Republic. The city celebrated its 300th anniversary in 1962 as part of the USSR, and its name changed to Ivano-Frankivsk. The new name commemorated the great Ukrainian writer and social activist, who did much to the preserve the Ukrainian language and culture.\n
In times of prosperity, Ivano-Frankivsk was a large trade and handiwork center, attracting representatives from the many nations. Its Jewish, Armenian and Polish communities were the largest. The city’s diverse character could not help but be reflected in its appearance: buildings of various architectural styles decorated Ivano-Frankivsk, giving the city its unique charm. But in the early 20th century, when severe fighting broke out all over the city, some historic buildings were destroyed, and later rebuilt in new architectural style. Yet Ivano-Frankivsk is still notable for its delicate elegance and allure.\n
The heart of the city, customary for European towns, is the Market Square, surrounded by charming old houses. The square’s architectural ensemble is reminiscent of Lviv’s, which is why Ivano-Frankivsk is often called ""Little Lviv.” In the center of the square stands the Town Hall - the only one in Ukraine that was built in the modernist style. The original town hall appeared here in the 17th century, but it was later rebuilt several times, settling on its current look in 1932. Today, the town hall houses a few pieces taken from the local history museum. If you choose to visit, you will find a collections of ancient furniture, weapons and books, as well as a tourist information center. One of the most famous fountains in Ivano-Frankivsk, the Egg Fountain, stands in front of the Town Hall.\n
The main gems of the city's sacral architecture are concentrated near the Market Square. Built in the 18th century, in the Late Baroque style, the building of the former Armenian Church holds a special place. In Soviet times, the Museum of Religion and Atheism was inside. Now, it is a functional Orthodox cathedral called the Holy-Pokrovsky.\n
The Church of Virgin Mary, the oldest building of Ivano-Frankivsk, stands nearby. It was built in the 17th century as a burial vault for the Potocki family. The building has since been converted to an art museum; inside, you will find Galicia icons, works of West Ukrainian classical painters, as well as the masterpieces of Polish, Austrian, German, and Italian painters. Next door is the Baroque Church of the Holy Resurrection (a Greek Catholic cathedral), rebuilt from the remains of a Jesuit church.\n
In addition to fascinating historic and architectural riches, Ivano-Frankivsk is known for its leisurely and harmonious life. This quality is pleasurable before heading off to conquer the snow-covered slopes of the Carpathians!
"
</string>
    <string name="Rivne">"Picturesque and cozy Rivne, one of the most ancient cities in Ukraine, could easily have been in the running for the title of the country’s most attractive place. But cruel history had other plans: the majority of is ancient buildings, which comprised its cultural heritage, were ruined or severely damaged during World War II. Fortunately, some of Rivne’s historic and architectural monuments survived, and are today – along with the city’s fantastic panoramas – its main treasure.\n
Rivne was first mentioned in history in 1283, as one of the cities of the Kingdom of Galicia–Volhynia. But there is reason to believe that its birth year came a quarter-century earlier. There is disagreement between three stories about where the city took its name. The first, and the most widespread, claims that the city’s name comes from its location on the flatlands (“rivne” means “flat” in Ukrainian). The second attributes the name’s origin to the massive ravines that guarded the city in ancient times. And according to the third, the city owes its name to the city’s former lords, Ostrogski princes, who purchased the city to even out their estate (“rivne” also means “exact” in Ukrainian).\n
Just like most of western Ukraine, the city had a complex past, constantly changing hands – two neighboring states, Lithuania and Poland, kept taking it from one another. In the 15th century, Rivnecame under the control of Semon Nieswicki, a Volhynian prince; after his death it became the property of his wife - Maria Nieswicka. It was during her reign, that the city was granted Magdeburg Rights and the right to hold annual fairs, which contributed to the city’s economic prosperity.\n
But the prosperity did not last long – during the next century, Rivne suffered from the Cossacks’ destructive invasion, terrible fires and the plague. In the late 18th century, the Russian Empire took control of the city, and in 1939, it became a part of Soviet Ukraine. After that, it lived through the most difficult part of its history: during World War II, the Nazis made Rivne the capital of occupied Ukraine. Several concentration camps were built on its territory, where people were exterminated en masse. Today, at the sight of the largest camp stands a Memorial to the Victims of Fascism.\n
The war’s destruction did not spare Rivne’s architecture, and many buildings and monuments were destroyed. The wooden Dormition Church, the city’s most ancient temple, is among the few survivors. It is known for its two story bell tower and for the so-called “chain of moral values,” to which criminals were chained in the 18th century until they publicly confessed and their sins were forgiven.\n
Another of Rivne’s architectural gems is the splendid Resurrection Cathedral, built on the territory of an ancient wooden church by the order of Emperor Alexander III, who himself partook in the cathedral’s construction. The marvelous St. Antoniy Catholic Church, which still has the original clock on its façade, reminds the visitors of the city’s medieval history; today, the building houses the Organ Music Hall. And its title as one of the greenest cities in Ukraine is supported by the Shevchenko Park, which 30 hectares large. It is a true masterpiece of garden art, and it became a favorite place to relax for both locals and visitors.\n
In spite of its difficult past, Rivne managed to preserve its unique charm. You feel it while walking through its streets, admiring its estates and watching its leisurely atmosphere from one of its quaint cafes. And should it so happen that Rivne does not win you over with its landmarks, it is sure to impress you with its hospitality!\n
"
</string>
    <string name="Lutsk">"The heart of Volyn is Lutsk, one of the most ancient, mysterious and charming cities in Ukraine. It is well known for its rich history, which determined the city’s appearance. Today, Lutsk manages to harmoniously combine the monumentality of Soviet architecture with the grace of ancient buildings that continue to preserve Kyivan Rus’ and Medieval Europe’s spirit. The richness of its history and architecture is comparable to those of Lviv and Kyiv.\n
History has not preserved the precise year of the city’s appearance, but it was first written about in 1085. An old text recounted the tale of a city whose massive fortress was able to withstand a 6 month-long siege by the Poles. The citadel itself, according to historians, was built in 1000 by Vladimir, the prince ofKyiv. At that time, the city’s name was Luchesk, derived from the word “luka,” meaning “an arc or bend (of a river)”.\n
In the 14th century, Lutsk was a part of the Grand Duchy of Lithuania and became its second most important city. Under Lithuanian rule, the city flourished, mostly due to its favorable location on a trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Byzantine Empire. Having turned into a large trade center, Lutsk became a magnet for domestic and foreign merchants, and, as a result, acquired a very diverse population. The Polish and German quarters appeared at this time, enriching Lutsk’s architectural beauty. Both Poland, which controlled Lutsk in the 16th and 17th centuries, and the Russian Empire, which took over a century later, contributed to the city’s unique aesthetic.\n
Lutsk’s historic area is a protected national treasure. It houses numerous historic, architectural and religious landmarks. The old and new parts of Lutsk are divided by the beautiful Lesia Ukarainka Street, which leads to the city’s main attraction, the Lubart Castle. It is one of ten oldest fortifications of not only Ukraine, but of the whole Europe. Moreover, it is one of the very few monuments of times of Lithuanian rule on Ukrainian territory, and it has survived until now almost unchanged. Several museums lie on the castle’s territory: the Armory Museum, the Book Museum, the Art Gallery and, the most unusual, Museum of Bells. In its collection, you can find one of the country’s oldest bells.\n
The gem of the historic city’s architectural ensemble is the splendid St. Peter and Paul Cathedral, built in the 17th century as part of a Jesuit monastic complex. The splendor of its decor and the luxury of its interior, richly decorated with sculptures and impressive frescos, continue to amaze its visitors. The church’s underground tunnels are also intriguing; they are multilayered and stretch on for kilometers. It is said that during restive times, the tunnels served as a secret passage out of the city. These dungeons are often compared to the netherworld. They are dimly lit and are littered with bones and sculls. You can enter the tunnels only on a tour.\n
Another of Lutsk’s sacral masterpieces is the Saint Trinity Cathedral. It appeared in the 18th century as a Catholic church in a Bernardine monastery; its features are reminiscent of Rococo. But after the Bernardine order was abolished, and the temple passed to the Orthodox church, and it was rebuilt in the late Baroque style.\n
The representatives of different cultures and religions that used to live in Lutsk, all left their marks in the form of distinctive architectural monuments. This explains why today, in the city’s historical center, besides Christian shrines, you can see a synagogue and a Protestant church, as well as a Karaite kenesa.\n
Lutsk is also famous for its bright festivals, national fairs, and medieval tourneys that take place in theLubart Castle. Such evens allow the guests to not only admire the centuries-old cathedrals and medieval streets, but to also feel the festive atmosphere of the time.\n
"
</string>
    <string name="Uzhgorod">"Ancient Uzhgorod is often called the “window to Europe.” It is little wonder, as it is situated in the heart of Zakarpattia – at the bottom of the majestic Carpathian Mountains and close to the border with Slovakia. Its unique location and multicultural influence have made it one of the most attractive places in western Ukraine. Here, the eclectic architecture of the Austro-Hungarian period is interwoven with buildings of Czechoslovakian constructivist and Soviet modernist styles, next to which blossom splendid Japanese cherry trees and magnolias.\n
The mountain river Uzh gave the city its name (until the 19th century it was known by the name Ungvar, which in Hungarian means the ""castle on Uzh River""), and it divides the city into two parts: the right and left banks. On the right bank stands the old city, which attracts the tourists with a collection of interesting historic and architectural monuments.\n
Uzhgorod appeared on the hills near the Carpathians over a thousand years ago, with the construction of a citadel, which became the residence of Old Russian prince Laborets, as Zakarpattia was at that time a part of Kyivan Rus. Over time, the castle grew and turned into flourishing city, soon becoming a part of Hungarian kingdom. The following four centuries it was developed by Italian aristocrats, the Drugeths counts. It was precisely during their reign that the castle got its current appearance. Since the 17th century, the expanding city played the role of the eastern gate of the Hapsburg Empire.\n
The Austrian reign gave Uzhgorod many architectural masterpieces, but the city’s biggest draw is still the ancient Citadel. It is one of the best-preserved fortifications in Ukraine. The citadel is constructed as trapezium (trapezoid), with impregnable 15 meter-high (50 feet) bastions. Its main compound is a three-story Renaissance building with four corner towers. A prison and a torture chamber used to occupy its dungeon. Today, the Local History Museum can be found in the Uzhgorod castle, along with a tasting room for the famous Zakarpattia wines.\n
Not far from the castle there is another unique landmark, the Trans-Carpathian Museum of Folk Architecture and Heritage. Original wooden buildings still stand here, representing the ethnic traditions of different nations that inhabited Zakarpattia. Among them, you will find tidy Guzul houses, a school, a windmill, and a watermill, and – the main treasure of the museum – St. Michael's wooden church from the 18th century, with its uncanny architecture.\n
Among the most captivating sacral buildings in Uzhgorod are the Holy Cross Cathedral and the elegant Roman Catholic Church of St. George, which was built on the ruins of a Lutheran church.\n
Uzhgorod is known as one of the greenest cities in Ukraine. In spring and summer, it is smothered by the lush greenery of numerous public gardens and exotic parks. You can also find the longest in Europe Linden Tree Alley, stretched out on both embankments.\n
Several pedestrian areas were created in the city so that tourists could peacefully admire its delicate architecture. The comfortable and subdued atmosphere invite leisurely strolls around the city’s historic center. And, of course, you can always take a break from the sights in one of the city’s amazing cafes that serve Zakarpattia’s famous coffee. Many visitors confess that the coffee’s taste, along with Uzhgorod’s unique sights landmarks, can become one of their brightest recollections of the city.\n
"
</string>
    <string name="Kamianets">"No epithet is able to describe fully the splendor of this ancient city, which no other city can match, even in Europe. Founded on an island, which was created by the Smotrych River bend, Kamianets-Podilskyi has a history, which has formed its diverse appearance. An incredible quantity of amazing 11th – 19th centuries' monuments and landmarks are concentrated on the territory of the Old City. They are a big reason why this city is on the list of UNESCO World Heritage Sites.\n
For over a thousand years, Kamianets-Podilskyi, located at the crossing of European trade routes and influenced by different cultures, had been a frontier castle, for which the East and the West fought constantly. The first fortification buildings appeared here in times of Kyivan Rus. However, most consider the city to have been founded in 1362 by the Lithuanian Koryatowicz princes. Legend has it that while out hunting, the brothers chased a beautiful deer, which led them to an unusual island surrounded by a deep canyon. In that place, a location saved by nature from outer threats, the Lithuanian princes decided to build a fortress.\n
The city grew so rapidly, that it soon turned into a large trade and craft center and began to compete withKyiv and Lviv. But Kamianets-Podilskyi experienced real prosperity in the 15th century, when it passed to Poland. At that time, three ethnic communities lived here - Poles, Armenians and Ukrainians - each of which decorated its neighborhoods with distinct architecture. During the Polish period, Kamianets-Podilskyi became known for its impenetrability. According to legend, a Turkish sultan, who had tried in vain to enter the city, asked the local citizens: ""Who built this fort?"" ""The God himself did!"" - was the answer. ""So let God conquer it!” - the sultan conceded.\n
Ironically, in 1672 the fortress surrendered to the Turks, who left a big imprint on the city during their 27 years of governance. Later, in 1699, Kamianets-Podilskyi returned to the guardianship of Poland, and a century later it passed to the Russian Empire.\n
Despite the twists in history, Kamianets-Podilskyi has managed to preserve its priceless buildings almost unchanged. The main sight is still the Ancient Fortress, considered to be one of the best samples of fortification buildings in Eastern Europe. Massive walls and bastions continue to inspire with their might and majesty. Among the fort towers, the ones that stand out are the Black Tower, which contains a 40-meter well, and the Karmeliukova Tower, which is the tallest tower and was named in the 19th century after its prisoner - Ukrainian national hero Ustym Karmeliuk.\n
In the towers and dungeons of the fortress are unique exhibitions, which brightly illustrate the pages ofKamianets-Podilskyi’s history: scenes of medieval trials, defenses of the fort, and weapons collections are all depicted. The “Antiquities of Podolia” exposition, describing the past of the region, is especially interesting. The castle bridge that leads to the fortress is separate tourist attraction on its own. It is often called the Turkish bridge, because in 17th century, when the Ottomans ruled the city, the bridge was considerably rebuilt.\n
The sacral architecture of Kamianets-Podilskyi is no less impressive – it fascinates with its richness and variety of represented cultures. A special place among the treasures of the city belongs to the Armenian Cathedral and to the St. Peter and Paul Catholic Church, an example of the beauty that combination of two different religious architectures can bring. During the Ottomans’ brief stay, the cathedral was turned into mosque. Since that time, it has been supplemented by a Turkish minaret. The complex of the Dominican Monastery also bears the imprints of different epochs and styles. And St. Nicolas' Catholic Church, included in the complex, is considered to be one of the most ancient city temples.\n
Because of so many historic monuments, Kamianets-Podilskyi gives you the opportunity to dive into a truly medieval atmosphere. And in order to get the most out of this wonderful city, you should visit it during a holiday or festival, which take place here almost all year round!
"
</string>
</resources>
